(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T01:58:00.148431",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
だって僕は星だから stellar stellar
'Cause I'm a star, stellar stellar,
きっと君はもう気づいていたのさ
I'm sure you had already noticed.
僕の心の奥で描いた
Drawn deep within my heart,
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
this is a cliché monologue I'll tell you now.
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say,
壊せない壁があったんだ
and walls I could never break down—
ずっとさ
always.
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
The scent of morning wafting in the air
どうしようもなく憎らしくて
is so unbearably hateful to me,
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて 震えていた
I sat in the corner of my room, hugging my knees and trembling.
太陽なんていらないから 明けないでいて
I don't need the sun, so please don't let dawn break—
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
reach out your hand so it reaches someone.
僕だって君と同じ 特別なんかじゃないから
I'm just like you, nothing special at all,
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
so yeah, I'll sing to the night, stellar stellar.
わけもなく泣きたくなるよな
For no reason at all, I feel like crying,
満たしさと寂しさだけを口移して
feeding each other only with fulfillment and loneliness.
気付けてさ 温め合うんだ
We notice each other and warm one another up,
もう二度と離れてしまわないように
so we never drift apart again.
ねぇ 正解とか間違いとか 今は何もわからないけど
Hey, I don't know what's right or wrong right now,
一つだけ確かなのは 私がいるということ
but the one thing for sure is that I am here.
近づいた分だけ 離れていく夢さえ
Even dreams pull away the closer I get to them—
今ならその迷いごと 笑える気がするから
but now I feel like I can even laugh at that hesitation.
孤独に輝いた 一人ぼっちの星が
The lonely, shining, solitary star
終わらない夜には ひとりきりの朝には
In the endless night, in the solitary morning,
隣ではなうように 涙がこぼれないように
so I'm not lonely beside you, so tears don't spill,
孤独に輝いた ひとりぼっちの星が
the lonely, shining, solitary star
ここにいるよと叫んで 歌になった
cried out "I'm right here" and turned into a song.
いつか誰かの夜を 照らすように
So that one day it might illuminate someone's night,
照らせるように
so that it can shine upon them.
刺すように キミの背中
Piercing your back like a needle,
見つめているだけじゃ Dreaming girl
just staring at you, Dreaming girl.
鉤付けのEyes 昨日よりもっと
Hooked eyes, even more than yesterday,
ああ愛しい 触れない 距離感
ah, how lovely, this unreachable distance.
あなたの目に映る 可愛い私
The cute me reflected in your eyes—
この瞬間を切り裂いて壊して
cut through this moment and break it.
ロマンスは殺した
Romance is dead,
足りない 聞かせて 今だけは
not enough, let me hear it, just for now.
宵に甘えて
Spoiling in the night,
飲み口付けに
with a lip-to-lip kiss—
マスクの着用にご協力ください
Please cooperate by wearing a mask.
COCOAを使用しているため携帯電話の電源はオフにせずマナーモードに設定してください
Since COCOA is in use, please set your phone to manners mode instead of powering it off.
撮影、録音、録画は禁止とさせていただきます
Photography, audio recording, and video recording are prohibited.
公演中に声を出しての応援はご遠慮ください
Please refrain from cheering aloud during the performance.
公演中は自席のままで立ってご観覧いただけます
You may stand at your own seat to watch during the performance.
公演中は席の移動をお控えください
Please refrain from moving from your seat during the performance.
宵に甘えて 飲み口付けに
Spoiling in the night, with a lip-to-lip kiss—
意味なんてないの 抑えられない衝動って
there's no meaning, it's an impulse I can't hold back.
ロマンスの果て
At the end of romance...
独自のせかいは
Your unique world
妙にきらめいていて どんな毒も飲ませたら
is strangely dazzling; if you let me drink any poison,
ねぇ このまま連れ出してくれない
hey, won't you take me away just like this?
攫って見せて この隙も迷って迷って 黒色に怯えて
Show me, snatching me away; even this gap, hesitating, trembling in the black.
誰のままじゃ 行かないで
Don't leave me as nobody's!
足りない 聞かせて 今だけは
Not enough, let me hear it, just for now.
宵に甘えて 飲み口付けに
Spoiling in the night, with a lip-to-lip kiss—
意味なんてないの 抑えられない衝動って
there's no meaning, it's an impulse I can't hold back.
ロマンスの果て
At the end of romance...
病んだ感情 さっきまでのヒステリックな間違い
Sick emotions, the hysterical mistakes up until just now—
喧騒を脱いで きらめき取り戻す
strip away the hustle and bustle, and reclaim the sparkle.
さあジョイナス 日常を忘れるストリーミング
Come on, join us, streaming that makes you forget daily life.
心地いい 捩じ切りの音楽たちを 散りばめジェリー 輝きで満たすよ
Comfortable, twisted music scattered about; fill it with the sparkle of jelly.
テイクオフ 今夜スイートになろうよ
Take off, let's become sweet tonight.
始まってくれるマジで キミとスィートになるんだ 盛り上がろう
It's truly starting, let's become sweet with you, get hyped!
永久早い音を通って 味覚は始まったばかり
Passing through eternal fast sounds, our taste has only just begun.
永久早い冷めてくよ さあ一緒にファイト
Eternally fast, it's cooling down, come on, fight together!
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become,
stellar stellar
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure that you've already seen through it all.
僕の心の奥で描いた
This script hidden deep down in my heart...
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
a clichéd monologue.
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There are so many things I couldn't say.
壊せない壁があったんだずっとさ
There were walls I could never climb beyond.
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
Sensing the scent of morning wafting in the air,
どうしようもなく憎々しくて
I tried to fight it, filling me with hate.
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていた
I sat in a corner and cried into my knees, trembling.
太陽なんかいらないから
I don't need the sunshine, don't want it.
明けないでいてで
Can dawn please stay away?
その手を伸ばして
Hold your hand out all the way,
誰かに届くように
reach out to make someone feel.
僕だって君と同じ特別なんじゃないから
We're very alike, you and me, neither of us is special.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night, stellar stellar,
ありったけの輝きで
shining as bright as any eye can take,
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まらない
my music will never ever be stopped tonight.
そうだよ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be was never
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
a Cinderella who waits forever,
迎えに行く王子様だ
but the prince who goes and gets things done.
だって僕は星だからなんて、ありふれた話なんだ
Just like the shooting star I have become.
理想だけ書き連ねていた
Idealistic thoughts written down,
ノートの隅に眠るほんのワンシーンだ
a trivial scene sleeping inside a notebook.
きっとあの星も泣いてるんだよ
I'm sure the stars in the sky are letting tears fall.
明日なんて来ないままでいてで
Can tomorrow never come, can it please stay away?
その手を伸ばして誰かに届くように
Hold your hand out all the way, reach out and make someone feel.
本当に大切なものは目に見えないみたいなんだよ
The truly important things are invisible to the naked eye.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night, stellar stellar,
ありのまま考えないでで
just true to myself, make no mistake.
今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
The music can never, ever be stopped tonight.
そうだよ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be was never
救いに行くヒーローだ
but a knight in shining armor.
あえかなヒロインじゃないさ
just a damsel in distress forever,
夢見がちなとぎ話 とぎ話
It is so fairytale, a total fantasy.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night, stellar stellar,
ありったけの輝きで
shining as bright as any eye can take,
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まらない
the music will never, ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕は愛を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through my love, stellar stellar,
巡り合えた一人一人と
in the midst of this world and all of space,
遠い迷路が明けるまで
the music can never, ever be stopped tonight.
きみと素敵にたりたりじゃまだ終われない
What I wanted to be was never
盛り上がれたりたりじゃ朝が来たって忘れない
a Cinderella who waits forever,
最後のたりたりじゃさ 一緒にファイト
but the prince who goes and gets things done.
こんなことも上手くできないに
Just like the shooting star I have become.
便利で快適で深海続けるテクノロジー伝えてよ
It is so fairytale, a total fantasy.
人肌のぬくもりねぇこのままずっと降りやまない雨の世界だ
So I sing now through this night, stellar stellar,
もう悲しくない 人慣れする生き物だから
shining as bright as any eye can take,
そう白紙になった青春の何ページ目だっけ
the music will never, ever be stopped tonight.
今君に会いたいと涙込み上げる
So I sing now through my love, stellar stellar,
そんなりけったり 注意散漫人生の天気だ
in the midst of this world and all of space,
新しい時代を乗りこなしていくんだ 透明で鮮明で叫び声上げる前乗り気で気だげに
the music can never, ever be stopped tonight.
失敗しては笑われてくもうこのままずっと降りやまない雨の世界だ
What I wanted to be was never
愛するしかないそれしかない機能じゃないから
a Cinderella who waits forever,
そう白紙になった青春の何ページ目だっけ忘れるもの思い出せない今は忘れそう
but the prince who goes and gets things done.
このままじゃ
Just like the shooting star I have become,
風の形見えない 見えないよあなたが
stellar stellar.
あなただって同じずっとなんてしてられない布気出すよこの身
I'm sure that you've already seen through it all.
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ トライアルデッキ＋ ホロライブプロダクション 好評発売中！
Weiss Schwarz Trial Deck+ Hololive Production is on sale now!
ブシロード
Bushiroad
D4DJ Groovy Mix
ホロライブ アルバム「Bouquet」全11曲グルミクに続々追加決定！
All 11 tracks from Hololive's album "Bouquet" are coming to Groovy Mix!
今宵はHalloween Night! などのいろんな楽曲を実装しちゃうんだって！
They're implementing various songs like "Ichiya wa Halloween Night!" and more!
コラボストーリーも読めちゃう！？
You can even read collaboration stories?!
ゲームBGM・インスト・カバー楽曲もDJ気分で遊べちゃう！つながろう、グルミクで！
Play game BGMs, instrumentals, and cover songs with DJ vibes! Connect with Groovy Mix!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ
Weiss Schwarz
ホロライブプロダクションのブースターパックでも止まらないヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiss Schwarz doesn't stop with Hololive Production's booster pack!
ブースターパック ホロライブプロダクション 好評発売中！
Booster Pack Hololive Production is on sale now!
ブシロード
Bushiroad
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star,
stellar stellar
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure you'd already noticed
僕の心の奥で描いた
What was drawn deep within my heart
それがこれから話す 陳腐なモノローグさ
That's the cliched monologue I'll tell you now
ずっと言えない言葉があった 壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
There were words I could never say, walls I could never break down
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star,
きっと君はもう気づいていた 僕の心の奥で描いた
I'm sure you'd already noticed what was drawn deep within my heart
それがこれから話す 陳腐なモノローグさ
That's the cliched monologue I'll tell you now
戸惑うというか ちょっと言えない言葉があった
There were things I was puzzled by, words I couldn't quite say
高鳴る鼓動が... 少し言えない言葉があった
My beating heart... there were words I couldn't quite say
だって僕は星だから stellar stellar
Because I am a star, stellar stellar
今宵音楽はずっとずっとやまない
The music tonight will surely, surely never stop
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star,
なんてありふれた話なんだ
What a clichéd story that is
ノートの隅に眠る本音
The true feelings sleeping in the corner of my notebook
マスクの着用にご協力ください
Please cooperate by wearing masks.
COCOAを使用しているため携帯電話の電源はオフにせずマナーモードに設定してください
Please set your mobile phones to manner mode without turning them off, as COCOA is in use.
撮影/録音/録画は禁止とさせていただきます
Photography, recording, and filming are prohibited.
公演中に声を出しての応援はご遠慮ください
Please refrain from cheering aloud during the performance.
公演中は自席の立ってご観覧いただけます
You can watch the performance standing at your seat.
公演中は席の移動をお控えください
Please refrain from moving seats during the performance.
今宵音楽はきっときっとやまない
The music tonight will surely, surely never stop
本日は 星街すいせい ファーストソロライブ STELLAR into the GALAXY...
Today is Hoshimachi Suisei's 1st Solo Live "STELLAR into the GALAXY"...
本日はファーストソロライブにご来場いただきまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending the first solo live today.
記念すべき私、星街すいせいの
To everyone looking forward to my,
ファーストソロライブを楽しみにしてくださっている皆さん、本日はどうぞよろしくお願いいたします。
Hoshimachi Suisei's memorable first solo live, thank you for your support today.
さて、公演を最後まで楽しんでいただくために、皆さまへいくつかご案内をさせてください。
Now, to ensure you enjoy the concert all the way to the end, please allow me to give you a few instructions.
まず初めに、ロビー客席内ではマスク着用が必須になりますので、マスクのご持参をお願いいたします。
First of all, wearing a mask is mandatory in the lobby and seating area, so please bring your mask.
公演中の声援、声援は、新型コロナウイルス感染予防の視点からご遠慮ください。
Please refrain from cheering during the performance from the perspective of preventing COVID-19 infection.
是非、拍手での応援をお願いいたします。
Please show your support with applause.
また、会場内では係員の指示に従ってください。
Also, please follow the instructions of the staff inside the venue.
客席内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ジャンプ等の危険行為、ルールに反したコンサートライトの使用は禁止となります。
Mosh pits, dives, jumps, and other dangerous acts, as well as rule-breaking light use, are prohibited.
これらの行為を守れない場合、公演が中断する場合もございますので、ご了解とご協力をお願いいたします。
If these rules cannot be followed, the performance may be interrupted, so your cooperation is appreciated.
このほか、会場内では携帯電話はマナーモードにしていただきますようお願い申し上げます。
In addition, please keep your mobile phones on manner mode inside the venue.
本公演は映像配信及び写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席のお客さまの様子が映り込む場合がございます。
Cameras for streaming and photography will enter the venue, and audience members may be captured on camera.
これら映像や写真はプロモーション等に使用される可能性がございますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
Please note that these videos and photos may be used for promotions.
ペンライトは周りのお客さまのご迷惑にならないよう、ご配慮をお願いいたします。
Please be considerate so that your penlight does not bother surrounding guests.
頭の上にだしたり、大きく左右に振り回されますと、後ろのお客さまや周りのお客さまのご迷惑となる場合がございます。
Raising it above your head or swinging it widely may disturb guests behind or around you.
係りのものが注意させていただく場合がございますので、ご了解ください。続いて、注意事項をお伝えします。
Staff may caution you about this, so please understand. Next, we will convey important notices.
本ライブの録音、録画、未来配信や違法アップロードは固くお断りいたします。
Recording, filming, future streaming, or illegal uploading of this live performance is strictly prohibited.
また、会場現地で本番中のライブの様子を撮影することは、演出の都合上、禁止とさせていただきます。
Also, photographing the live performance on-site during the show is prohibited for production reasons.
なにとぞご了解ください。ただし、配信でご覧いただいている皆さまにおかれましては、スクリーンショットを撮影いただき、SNSで画像付きで感想をご投稿いただくことは歓迎します。
Please understand. However, for those watching via stream, you are welcome to take screenshots and post your impressions with images on SNS.
本公演のハッシュタグは「#輝く星街」です。ぜひハッシュタグを使ってライブを盛り上げてください。
The hashtag for this performance is "#KagayakuHoshimachi". Please use the hashtag to liven up the live.
また、ライブ配信についてデータ通信量が多くなることが想定されるため、スマートフォンでご覧になる場合には、Wi-Fiでのご利用を推奨いたします。
Also, since data traffic is expected to increase for live streaming, if viewing on a smartphone, using Wi-Fi is recommended.
インターネット回線の接続が不安定な場合は、配信動画のクオリティを保証できません。
If your internet connection is unstable, we cannot guarantee the quality of the streamed video.
最善の準備を行いライブ配信を実施いたしますが、生配信の特性上、不慮の障害で映像の乱れや一時停止等が起こる可能性があります。あらかじめご了解ください。
We will prepare as best as possible for the live stream, but unexpected issues may cause video distortion or temporary pauses.
終演後は規制退場を行います。
After the concert, regulated exit will be conducted.
席の方でスタッフの指示があるまでお待ちください。
Please wait at your seat until instructed by staff.
以上のことが守られない場合、安全確保のため、公演を一時中断もしくは中止させていただくこともございますので、あらかじめご了解ください。
If the above cannot be followed, for safety reasons, the performance may be temporarily suspended or canceled.
最後に、体調の優れない場合など何かございましたら、早めにお近くのスタッフにお申し付けください。また、地震などの緊急時にはスタッフが誘導いたします。
Finally, if you feel unwell or have any issues, please notify nearby staff early. Also, in emergencies such as earthquakes, staff will guide you.
スタッフの指示があるまで、席にてお待ち下さいますようお願いいたします。
Please wait at your seat until staff instructions are given.
さて、私からのご案内は以上となります。開演まであともう少し、皆さん、ライブに向けた準備はできていますか？
Now, that concludes my guidance. There's just a little while until the curtain opens, everyone, are your preparations ready?
ライトの電池は入ってますか？ タオルはお手元にお持ちですか？ Tシャツ着てますか？
Are the batteries in your lights? Do you have your towel at hand? Are you wearing your t-shirt?
声出しはだめですよ。声を出し、完成なしで心の中で叫んでみてください。
Raising your voice is not allowed. Without shouting or making noise, try shouting in your heart.
配信の方たちは、ご近所さんまたはお母さんにご配慮の上、叫んでください。
Those streaming, please shout with consideration for your neighbors or mother.
それでは、開演まで今しばらくお待ちください。星街すいせいでした！
Well then, please wait a little while until the curtain opens. It was Hoshimachi Suisei!
星が揺らいで 夢を見ている
Stars are wavering, dreaming a dream,
焦がれたその声が呼んでるの
the voice I longed for is calling me.
キラめくカラー まとった君に
To you, draped in shimmering colors,
届けるこのメロディ
I deliver this melody.
このままじゃね 終れない
I can't end just like this,
スペシャルなステージ 踊り明かすの
dancing the night away on a special stage.
このままじっとしていられない
I can't stay still like this.
明かりがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light flickered on, flickered on,
天を彩った彗星が綺麗だ
the comet adoring the heavens is so beautiful.
僕の吐いた白い息のように 消してしまえたらな
If only I could erase it, like my white breath in the cold.
押し殺して深く沈んだ
Suppressed and sinking deep down,
泣き声さえ聴こえているから
even my weeping voice can be heard.
君を刺した不安も苦痛も
All the anxiety and pain that pierced you
僕の青色で塗り潰して
I'll paint over with my blue,
全部涙になって
turning it all into tears
星の海を流れていったんだ
flowing away into the sea of stars.
果てしない闇の中に
In the endless darkness,
そっと青を添えたら ほら
if I gently add a touch of blue—look.
彗星が夜を跨いだ
A comet strides across the night.
彗星がふと墜ちたんだ
A comet suddenly fell from the sky.
誰もいない夜の空を決めた
It decided upon an empty night sky.
深く沈まった街の中へ 降り注ぐのは 誰の悲しみだろう
Into the deeply sunken town, raining down—whose sadness could it be?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The stars drew arcs once more and flew,
靄のかかった思考を晴らして
clearing away clouded thoughts.
「いつかまた会える」なんて言えなかった
I couldn't bring myself to say, "We'll meet again someday."
星が降ったあとの街、僕はまだ
In the town after the falling stars, I am still...
星が降ったあと伸ばす僕はまだ
Stretching out my hands after the stars fell, I am still...
黒く澄みながらの空を
Looking up at the dark, clear sky,
箒星が彩るように
as if a comet is coloring it,
君をさした不安も苦痛も
all the anxiety and pain that pierced you
僕の青色で塗り潰して
I'll paint over with my blue,
君の涙をそっと星の海に流し込むんだ
gently letting your tears flow into the sea of stars.
尾を引いたその光が誰かをまた救うから
That trailing light will save someone once again, so—
彗星がもし選ぶのなら
If a comet were to choose,
この空をずっと君にあげる
I'd give this entire sky to you.
言えない言葉の尾を引いて
Trailing the tail of words I cannot speak,
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
raining down—whose sadness could it be?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The stars drew arcs once more and flew,
街の景色を奪い去るように
as if snatching away the town's scenery.
君とまた会えるなら僕はそうだな
If I could meet you again, I suppose...
星の名前をひとつ受け止めよう
I would embrace a single star's name.
寂しさが溢れそうになること
Whenever loneliness is about to overflow,
天球で離れ離れでも僕らは繋がってるから
even if separated across celestial spheres, we are connected.
彗星がもし選ぶのなら
If a comet were to choose,
誰もいない夜の空を決めた
it decided upon an empty night sky.
深く沈まった街の中へ 降り注ぐのは
Into the deeply sunken town, raining down—
誰の悲しみだろう 星はまた弧を描いて
whose sadness could it be? The stars drew arcs once more...
街の景色を奪い去るように 君とまた会えるなら
as if snatching away the town's scenery. If I could meet you again,
靄のかかった思考を晴らして
clearing away clouded thoughts,
いつか歌えるなんて言えなかった
I couldn't bring myself to say we'd sing together someday.
星が降ったあと伸ばす僕はもっとずっと君の行方を探してた
Stretching out my hands after the stars fell, I kept searching for your whereabouts all this time.
本日は、星街すいせい 1st ソロライブ "STELLAR into the GALAXY" サポートされたるぶしロードにご来場いただきまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending Hoshimachi Suisei's 1st Solo Live "STELLAR into the GALAXY" supported by Bushiroad today.
大変長らくお待たせいたしました。
Thank you very much for waiting.
本公演は、まもなく開演いたします。
This performance will begin shortly.
皆さん、一緒に盛り上がる準備はできてますかー？
Everyone, are you ready to get hyped together?
ペンライトと拍手で答えてくださーい！
Answer with your penlights and applause!
最後まで一緒に楽しみましょう！
Let's enjoy it together until the very end!
あらためまして、
Once again,
星街すいせい 1st ソロライブ
Hoshimachi Suisei 1st Solo Live
STELLAR into the GALAXY
Supported by ブシロード
Supported by Bushiroad
開演します！スタート！
The show is starting! Start!
誰しもが この街で孤独だった。
Everyone was lonely in this city.
道行く人々はすれ違い、
People passing each other by on the streets,
想い描く未来も かすみがかった。
and the future we pictured was hazy.
空で輝いているはずの星は 雲に覆われて見えない。
The stars that should be shining in the sky are covered by clouds and can't be seen.
そして僕は 今日も何者にもなれないでいる。
And I am still nothing today as well.
パッと弾けた感情に
These feelings that burst from within me,
言い訳を並べて過ごした
all this time, I was just making excuses.
葛藤も知らない街灯り
The city lights, knowing nothing of inner conflicts,
君だけだって嘘をついた
even if it was just to you, I told a lie.
信じたくないままで踊っている
Dancing like I don’t even want to believe it,
示すために連ね続けた言葉
these words I kept stringing together to show you.
見えないの ぼくがぼくのこの声が聞こえてる？
Can you hear my voice, from my invisible self?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすら透明で きっと不格好だけれど
Even my silhouette is transparent, and I’m sure it’s ungraceful, but still,
でも せめて声を枯らそう
at least let my voice grow hoarse.
必死に縋ってもずっと証を
No matter how desperately I cling, there is still no proof,
ねぇ ゴーストみたいだ
hey, I'm like a ghost.
散々怨んだ明るさと
The brightness that I hated so much,
意味ありげに伸びていく影
and the shadow stretching out with meaning.
淡々と過ぎ越した一粒の君の言葉で泣きたくなった
Your words, which passed by indifferently, made me want to cry.
大切にしたいものが零れていく
The words I want to express while the things I cherish are spilling over,
示すままに繋がり続けたい言葉
the words I want to keep stringing together.
見えてるの ぼくがぼくのこの声が届いてる？
Can you see me? Is this voice of mine reaching you?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすら透明で きっと不格好だけれど
Even my silhouette is transparent and I’m sure it’s ungraceful, but still,
でも だから叫んで足掻いて
that's why I'm screaming, struggling,
裸足のままで走って ねぇ気付いて教えてよ答は
running barefoot, hey, notice me and tell me the answer.
だって僕は星だから
Because I'm a star!
stellar stellar
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure you've already noticed it by now,
僕の心の奥で描いた
Deep inside my heart...
それがこれから話す
That's what I'll talk about from now on.
陳腐なモノローグさ
A clichéd monologue.
ずっと言えない言葉があって 壊せない壁があったんだずっとさ
There were always words I couldn't say, walls I couldn't climb...
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
The scent of the morning...
どうしようもなく憎らしくてさ
Was somehow so hateful.
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていた
I sat in the corner of my room, hugging my knees and trembling.
太陽なんかいらないから 明けなまいでいて
I don't need the sun, please don't let dawn break.
その手を伸ばして
Reach out your hand...
誰かに届くように
So it can reach someone.
僕だって君と同じ特別なんじゃないから
I'm not special, just like you.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ
That's right, I sing to the night!
stellar stellar
ありったけの輝きで
With a brilliance that's all I have,
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まらない
Tonight, the music will never, ever stop.
そうだな僕がずっとなりたかったのは
What I always wanted to be...
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
Isn't the waiting Cinderella,
迎えに行く王子様だ
But the prince who comes to greet her.
だって僕は星だから
Because I'm a star!
stellar stellar
なんてありふれた話なんだ
Just a common story, you could say.
理想だけ書き連ねていた
I was just writing down my ideals.
ノートの隅に眠るほんのワンシーンだ
Just one scene sleeping in the margins of my notebook.
きっとあの星も泣いているんだ
I'm sure even those stars are crying.
明日なんて来ないままでいて その手を伸ばして
May tomorrow never come, let it stay just like this.
誰かに届くように
So it can reach someone.
本当に大切なものは目に見えないみたいなんだ
The truly important things are invisible to the eye.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ
That's right, I sing to the night!
stellar stellar
ありのまま考えないでで
Staying true to myself without a second thought,
今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
Tonight, the music surely, surely will never stop.
そうだな僕がずっとなりたかったのは
What I always wanted to be...
僅かなヒロインじゃないさ
Wasn't a frail heroine,
救いに行くヒーローだ
But a hero coming to the rescue.
夢見がちな童話話し
A fairytale dream.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ
That's right, I sing to the night!
stellar stellar
ありったけの輝きで
Shining as bright as any eye can take,
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まらない
Tonight, the music will never, ever stop.
そうさ僕は愛を歌うよ
That's right, I sing of love!
stellar stellar
その世界の真ん中で
In the very middle of that world,
今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
Tonight, the music surely, surely will never stop.
そうだな僕がずっとなりたかったのは
What I always wanted to be...
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
Isn't the waiting Cinderella,
迎えに行く王子様だ
But the prince who comes to greet her.
だって僕は星だから
Because I'm a star!
stellar stellar
踏んだり蹴ったり注意散漫人生の天気だ
Even if I stumble, even if I kick and trip,
新しい時代を乗りこなしこなして行くんだ
I'll overcome this new era and keep evolving.
鮮明で鮮明で叫び声上げるわ
Vividly, brightly, shouting out loud!
乗り切ってけがけに失敗しては笑っていく
Even if I stumble, even if I make mistakes,
もうこのままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
I'll never stop running through this world of rain.
愛するしかない それしかない 臆病じゃないから
I have no choice but to love it. That's the only way.
もうこのままじゃ...
I'm not cowardly, so I have no choice.
Even if I stumble, even if I make mistakes,
風の形見えない 見えないよ
Even if the shape of the wind is invisible, invisible...
あなただってあなただって同じ きっとだって捨てられない動き動き
You and I are the same, we can't just throw it away.
強よ このみ かけて このさ ないよ ないたってしょうがないさ
This movement is strong, I'll stake my desires on it,
もうこのままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
Even if I cry, I have no choice.
もう悲しくない 人は慣れる 息もできないほど
I'll never stop running through this world of rain.
そうさ白紙になった青春の真っ暗闇だけ
I have no choice but to love it. That's the only way.
だって僕は星だから
Because I'm a star,
stellar stellar
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure you had already noticed,
雨上がりの この世界が 眩しかったら
If this world after the rain was dazzling,
もう金輪際 振り返らない
I'll never look back ever again.
振り返らない 思い出とともに
I won't look back, together with my memories.
懐かしい 風に煽られ
Whipped by a nostalgic wind,
そしてまた君に 会いたい と願い
And wishing once more to see you,
かけていく
I keep running on.
なんて ありふれた話なんだ
What a run-of-the-mill story,
理想だけ書き連ねていた
I just kept writing down ideals.
ノートの隅に眠る ほんのワンシーンだ
Just a tiny scene sleeping in the margin of a notebook.
きっとあの星も泣いてるんだ
I'm sure that star is crying too.
明日なんて来ないままでいて
Can tomorrow never come, please stay away?
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
Hold your hand out all the way, reach out and make someone feel.
本当に大切なものは 目に見えないみたいなの
The truly important things in life are painfully invisible to the naked eye.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night so stellar stellar,
ありのまま考えないで 今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
Just true to myself, make no mistake. The music can never, ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be was never
あえかなヒロインじゃないさ
Just a frail heroine forever,
救いに行くヒーローだ
But a hero going to save the day.
夢見がちなおとぎ話 おとぎ話
It is so fairytale, a total fantasy, a total fantasy.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night so stellar stellar,
ありふれた輝きで 今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
Shining as bright as any eye can take, the music will never ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕は愛を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through my love so stellar stellar,
この世界 宇宙の真ん中で 今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
In the midst of this world and all of space, the music will never, ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be was never
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
A Cinderella who waits forever,
迎えに行く王子様だ
But the prince who goes and gets things done.
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become,
Just like the shooting star I have been all along,
stellar stellar
幻想 興奮の すなわち声 宇宙の裏
Illusions, excitement, in other words, voices from the other side of the universe.
白い煙に吹かれながら歌う 救い出せない迷いごと
Singing while blown away by white smoke, about stray matters that cannot be saved.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night so stellar stellar,
ありふれた輝きで 今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
Shining as bright as any eye can take, the music will never ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕は愛を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through my love so stellar stellar,
この世界 宇宙の真ん中で 今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
In the midst of this world and all of space, the music will never, ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be was never
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
A Cinderella who waits forever,
迎えに行く王子様だ
But the prince who goes and gets things done.
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become,
Just like the shooting star I have been all along,
stellar stellar
はい！
Yes!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
まずはね、3曲 歌わせていただきました！
First of all, we got to sing three songs!
いやー、今日めっちゃ寒くてさ
Man, it's super cold today, so...
なんか、寒すぎて、舞台袖にいるときから「寒い寒い寒い！」って
Like, it was so cold that even while standing in the wings, I was going 'So cold, so cold, so cold!'
寄ってたんですけど
I was saying...
ステージに 出て来たら
once you get out on stage,
だいぶ暑いです。
it's super hot!
(笑)
(laughs)
はい、ということで、
All right, so,
最初の挨拶からいきたいと思います。
let's start with our first greeting.
最初の挨拶と言ったらね、この場所にいる皆さんは 声を出したいあれがあると思うんですけど
When you talk about a greeting at a place like this, everyone wants to call out, right?
声を出せないと思うので、今日は声を出せないと思うので
Since you can't, let's say it together!
あのペンライトでね、今日も、かわいい！で
With a penlight, let's say, "You're so cute today!"
今日もかわいい！で 行きましょう。進めていきましょう。
"Today's so cute!" Let's go with that.
じゃあ行きますよ。
Let's go!
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石、アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
The asteroid that appeared like a comet, hololive's VTuber, Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃんはー！
Suichan wa--!
あー、わかる、わかる。
Ah, I get it, I get it.
あ、すごいわかる。
Ah, I totally get it.
あ、いいですね。今日もかわいい聞こえてきました。
Ah, it's great. Today's sounds so cute too!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ということで、星街すいせいファーストソロライブ「STELLAR into the GALAXY Supported By ブシロード」へようこそー！
And so, welcome to Hoshimachi Suisei's 1st Solo Live "STELLAR into the GALAXY Supported By Bushiroad"!
いやあ、念願のファーストソロライブ、しかもトイスピリットということで、本当にこの日を待ち望んで、もう何ヶ月も準備をしてまいりましたが、皆さん今どうですか？楽しいですか？
Yeah, my long-awaited 1st solo live, and with Toy's Spray, we've been looking forward to this day and preparing for months! How is everyone doing right now? Are you having fun?
わあ、ありがとう！
Yay, thank you!
いや、あのさ、
You know...
いや、なんかさっきね、モニターで見てたんだけど、なんかね、最前の一人人の人がね、椅子にね、なんか分からないけどぬいぐるみ？とかなんか置いてて、
Earlier, I was watching the monitor, and you know, someone right near the front seemed to have left a stuffed toy on their chair or something?
「なんだこれぬいぐるみ？」ってなってたので見てました。(笑)
I was watching them go, "What is that stuffed toy?!" (laughs)
あとね、あの、男性も女性もなんかもう半々くらいじゃないですか？だいぶ
Also, the ratio of men to women was about fifty-fifty, wasn't it? Quite...
はい、男性の人、挙手。
Okay, men, raise your hands!
いっぱーい！
Yay!
はい、女性の人、挙手。
Okay, women, raise your hands!
いっぱーい！
Yay!
うれしー！
I'm so happy!
あの、老若男女に、えー、人気な星街すいせいということでね、あの、
So, with popular Hoshimachi Suisei being so popular among both men and women,
やっぱりね、皆さんの声がないと、あの、受け取ってるのか受け取ってないのか、分かりませんね。(笑)
you know, without everyone's voices, I can't tell if you're receiving it or not! (laughs)
ありがとうございます。(笑)
Thank you! (laughs)
きっと今ね、受け取ってるでしょ。
I'm sure you're receiving it now.
あ、そしてね、あの、ちょっと電波を受信することができてですね、あの、コメントをね、コメントが読めるんですよ。なんて、はーい、草、パチパチ、かわいいよ、みたいな。いっぱいい、ちょっとね、見えます。電波を受信できます。
And also, since I'm able to receive radio waves, I can actually read the comments! It's like, "Hi! Grass, patch-patch, you're so cute!" I can see lots of them. I'm getting the radio waves!
ありがとう、配信の皆さんも！
Thank you, everyone watching the stream too!
ありがとうー！いや、楽しいね。もう、もう、なんか楽しいわ。もう楽しい。
Thank you! It's so much fun. It's just so much fun now.
はい、あのー、ぜひね、配信で見てくださってる皆さん、ハッシュタグ「#輝く星街」でたくさん呟いてください。
Yes, everyone watching the stream, please tweet a lot with the hashtag #ShiningHoshimachi!
なんかもうトレンド1位になったっていう、話題が、出たんですけど、本当ですか？本当ですか？やったー！ありがとうございます！
I heard it became number one on trending, is that true? Is it true? Yay! Thank you!
会場の皆さんはね、ぜひ呟かないぶ、たくさんペンライト振ってください。
Everyone at the venue, please tweet a lot and wave your penlights.
へへへへって、(笑)
Heh heh heh, like "Eheheh." (laughs)
はい、じゃあね、ライブタイトルにもね、あります通り、今回のライブはブシロード様にご協賛をいただいております。あ、ブシロード様、ありがとうございます！
Okay, so, as you can see in the live title, for this live, we are sponsored by Bushiroad! Thank you very much, Bushiroad!
今ね、見えてるかな？上のLEDに、ブシロードさんと私のコラボ情報が映ってるかなと思います。
Right now, if you look at the LED screen above, I think Bushiroad and my collaboration info is showing.
まずは、トレーディングカードゲームヴァイスシュヴァルツより、ホロライブプロダクションのパックが好評発売中です！
First, from the trading card game Weiß Schwarz, booster packs from Hololive Production are currently on sale!
私の白星サインカードも入ってるらしいよ。入手こんな感じらしいよ。これ。
It seems my own Hoshimachi Suisei card is included too. You can get it like this!
ぜひね、ぜひね、詳細はヴァイスシュヴァルツ公式ホームページをチェックしてみてください！
Please check the official Weiß Schwarz website for details!
さらに、スマートフォン向けリズムゲーム「D4DJ Groovy Mix」がもうすぐ1周年ということで、ホロライブコラボガチャも復刻するみたいです！やったー！
Furthermore, the rhythm game for smartphones D4DJ Groovy Mix is almost at its 1st anniversary, so the Hololive collaboration gacha is coming back! Yay!
さらに、星街すいせい「Stellar Stellar」がグルミクに本日10月21日実装されます！やったー！私のカードイラストもゲームを遊ぶだけでゲットできちゃいますので、ぜひぜひダウンロードしてみてくださいね！
And Hoshimachi Suisei's "Stellar Stellar" will be implemented in Groovy Mix today, October 21st! Yay! You can get my card illustration just by playing the game, so please download it!
というダイマを挟んだところで、YouTubeでご覧の皆さんは、ここで、お別れとなってしまいます！いやあ、寂しい！あ、寂しいの拍手お願いします。(笑)
With that big announcement, for those watching on YouTube, it's almost time to say goodbye! Aw, I'm lonely. I'd appreciate a lonely round of applause. (laughs)
今ね、YouTubeでちらみせ配信をしているんですけども、もうね、ちらみせは終わりということで、あの、ぜひね、続きがみたいなと思った方は、
Now, we're streaming a preview on YouTube, but since the preview is ending, if you want to see the rest...
SPWNって書いて
It's spelled "SPWN,"
スポーンって読むんですけど
and it's pronounced "Spawn,"
スポーンにて続きが見れますので
but you can watch the continuation on Spawn,
ぜひ概要欄をチェックしてみてください
so please check the description box!
した？ 多分した？
Did I? Probably did.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
謎の拍手ありがとうございます、助かります。
Thank you for the mysterious applause, it helps!
はい、ライブはまだまだこれからです。
Yes, the live is still just beginning.
ゲストとのデュエットやいろんな演出がね、
There are guest duets and all sorts of performances,
たくさんありますので公開しないように
so many that you won't want to regret missing them—
是非今のうちに買ってくださいね！
make sure to get your tickets now!
お水など飲みながら
"While drinking water..."
って書いてあるんでお水飲みます。
it says, so I'll drink some water.
飲みます
Drinking...
お水見えました、いま。
Can you see the water right now?
お水見えました？
Can you see the water?
あ、見え？
Oh, can you see?
見え？
Can you?
これな、星読みには見えないお水なんです。
This water is invisible to Astrologers.
星読みじゃない人にはお水が見えるかもしれない。
People who aren't Astrologers might see it, though.
ってことでね、あの、このマイクをちょっと今から置きたいと思います。
So, um, I'm going to put this microphone down now.
行きますよ。
Here I go!
マイクを置くのにいきますよって
Saying "Here I go to put the mic down,"
マイクをこれ行きますよ！行きますよ！パッ！
I'm going to put the mic down! Here I go! Bam!
はい無い！
There, it's gone!
無い！
Gone!
はいはいはい、じゃあね、
Alright, alright, well then,
まだまだたくさん歌いたい曲がありますんで、
we still have a lot of songs I want to sing,
いよいよ次の曲に行きたいと思います！
so we're finally going to move on to the next song!
最後まで盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's keep the energy going all the way to the end!
無料パートは終了いたしました ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free portion has ended. Thank you for watching!
無料パートは終了いたしました
The free part has ended.
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching!